A Finding Aid to the Leon Golub Papers, 1930s-2009, in the Archives of American Art AAA.goluleon
Archives of American Art
Leon Golub papers
1930s-2009
AAA.goluleon
Archives of American Art
16.5 Linear feet
The papers of painter, political activist, and educator Leon Golub are dated 1930s-2009 and measure 16.5 linear feet. His career as a painter and educator – and, to a far lesser extent, his personal interests and activities – are documented by correspondence, interviews, writings by Golub and other authors, subject files, printed material, and audiovisual recordings. Also included are biographical materials, personal business records, and photographs of Leon Golub and wife Nancy Spero. Posthumously dated items are mostly condolence letters, obituaries, printed material, and inventories of his work.
Golub, Leon, 1922-2004
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1930s-2006 (Boxes 1-2; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1955-2004 (Boxes 2-3; 0.9 linear foot)
Series 3: Interviews, 1967-2004 (Boxes 3-4; 0.8 linear foot)
Series 4: Writings, 1948-2003 (Boxes 4-5, 21; 1.1 linear foot)
Series 5: Subject Files, 1959-2005 (Boxes 5-11, OV 18; 6.2 linear feet)
Series 6: Personal Business Records, 1965-2009 (Boxes 11-12; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, circa 1950s-2009 (Boxes 12-16, 21, OV 19; 3.9 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1940s-2004 (Boxes 16-17, OV 20; 0.6 linear foot)
Biographical/Historical note
Leon Golub (1922-2004) was a painter in New York City known for figurative work with political content, an anti-war activist, and professor of art at Rutgers University.
Chicago native Leon Golub studied art history at the University of Chicago (BA 1942) before serving as a cartographer with the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers in Europe during World War II. Upon returning home, Golub became identified with Monster Roster, a group of Chicago artists who believed art must be grounded in real events in order to be relevant to the viewer and society, an idea he held throughout his life. At the School of the Art Institute of Chicago, Golub pursued his interest in painting (BFA 1949, MFA 1950) and met fellow student Nancy Spero whom he married in 1951. After graduation he began teaching at local colleges, exhibited in Chicago and New York, and served as chair of “Exhibition Momentum” (1950). The couple and their two sons lived in Italy from 1956-1957. In 1959 they moved to Paris and, while there, a third son was born. Upon returning to New York City in 1964, Golub became actively involved with the Artists and Writers Protest Against the War in Vietnam, other anti-war groups, and civil liberties organizations. While his painting style changed with time, Golub continued to explore power, violence and conflict, often working in series with titles such as Combats, Napalm, Mercenaries, Interrogation, and Riot.
He first participated in a group show with other veterans at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago in 1947, and soon was included in group and solo exhibitions throughout the United States and in Europe, including the Guggenheim Museum’s influential national traveling exhibition ”Younger American Painters” (1954-1956). Golub and Spero exhibited their work in tandem and collaborated on installations. He continued to participate in group shows including “Documenta IX” (2002). Golub's work is included in the permanent collections of museums throughout the world.
Golub began his teaching career soon after graduation, first at a junior college in Chicago. In the later 1950s he served briefly on the faculties of Illinois Institute of Technology School of Design and Indiana University; in the 1960s at the Tyler School of Art in Philadelphia, and Fairleigh Dickinson University in New Jersey. He began a long tenure at Rutgers University, School of Visual Arts in 1970 and retired in 1991. In the early 1990s, both Golub and Spero were affiliated with Sommerakademie in Salzburg. Golub wrote and spoke on art, politics, and social issues; he also published many articles, statements, and book reviews, as well as contributing introductions and essays for exhibition catalogs.
Awards and honors included the Skowhegan Medal for Painting (1988), Chicago Committee to Defend the Bill of Rights Award (1989), Dickinson College Arts Award (1992), National Foundation of Jewish Culture Visual Arts Award (1995), and Hiroshima Art Prize shared with Nancy Spero (1996). Golub was awarded honorary doctorates of Fine Arts by the School of the Art Institute of Chicago (1982), Swarthmore College (1985), College of St. Rose (1995), Trinity College (1999), and Pratt Institute (2000). He was elected a member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters (2002).
Leon Golub died in New York City August 8, 2004 from complications following surgery.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original materials requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Related Archival Materials note
Also among the holdings of the Archives of American Art are oral history interviews with Leon Golub conducted for the Archives of American Art by Bruce Hooten 1965 and Irving Sandler 1968 October 28-November 18. The Nancy Spero papers, 1940s-2009, bulk 1970-2009, include documentation of many of the couple's collaborative projects, joint exhibitions, their family, and shared interests.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter, political activist, and educator Leon Golub are dated 1930s-2009 and measure 16.5 linear feet. His career as a painter and educator – and, to a far lesser extent, his personal interests and activities – are documented by correspondence, interviews, writings, subject files, printed material, and audiovisual recordings. Also included are biographical materials, personal business records, and photographs of Leon Golub and his art work. Posthumously dated items are mostly condolence letters, obituaries, printed material, and inventories of his work.
Biographical materials consist largely of video documentaries about Leon Golub and his work, obituaries, and information about his 2004 memorial service and a larger memorial tribute held later. Also found are educational records, passports, curricula vitae.
Correspondence is mostly of a professional nature, focusing on exhibitions, projects, collectors, articles submitted for publication, Golub's work, speaking engagements, awards, gifts of artwork, studio visits, and travel arrangements. Correspondents include dealers, curators, art historians, critics, collectors, writers, and editors. Scattered throughout are a small number of letters concerning personal business and politics.
Interviews with Leon Golub and joint interviews with Leon Golub and Nancy Spero were conducted for a variety of purposes. They are preserved as transcripts, video, and sound recordings. Writings by Golub include manuscripts and notes for articles, catalog essays, and miscellaneous writings. Notes and texts for talks, lectures, and panel discussions, include some transcripts and recordings. Among the writings by other authors are a dissertation, a thesis, academic papers, notes, texts of speeches, and a recording of a lecture by an unidentified speaker.
Subject files reflect Golub’s professional and personal activities, interests and relationships. Of note are many files of "Images (source material)" used for a variety of artwork and projects. Personal business records documenting Golub’s artistic output include many inventories and lists, and a comprehensive register of work, information about consignments, loans, photo permissions, and gifts or donations. Also found are extensive mailing lists.
Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, and a variety of miscellaneous printed items. Most material is about/mentions Golub, and/or includes reproductions of his work. Scattered throughout are items concerning topics of interest to Golub, and articles written by him.
The majority of the photographic materials are color digital prints of Golub’s artwork. There are photographs of Leon Golub and Nancy Spero, family members, and friends and colleagues at exhibition events. Also found are a few photographs of Golub's plexibox sculptures.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Leon Golub papers were donated by Leon Golub in 1978; the majority of the papers were given in 2013 by The Nancy Spero and Leon Golub Foundation for the Arts via their sons Stephen, Philip and Paul Golub. Material loaned for microfilming in 1969 is included with the 2013 donation.
Spero, Nancy, 1926-2009; Art critics; Art dealers; Art historians; Art museum curators; Art--Collectors and collecting; Educators--New York (State)--New York; Interviews; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Political activists--New York (State)--New York; Sound recordings; Transcripts; Video recordings
- Biographical Material, 1930s-2006; Series 1; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes biographical documents such as school transcripts, curricula vitae, passports, and obituaries along with information about Golub's 2004 memorial service and a larger memorial tribute held many months later. There are multiple video documentaries about Golub and his work on 8 videocassettes and 2 videodiscs (DVD). The documentary "Leon Golub: The Late Works are the Catastrophes" is represented in multiple versions and excerpts. Also included is 1 videocassette of a family party.
  Arrangement note
  Biographical materials are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Additional biographical materials regarding son Paul Golub are found among the subject files (Series 5).
  - About Golub and His Work (Box 1)
    - "Leon Golub" and "Golub", undated; circa 1988; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Labels incomplete; may be duplicates of other works in this series.
    - "Golub: A Film on Art, Politics, and the Media", 1988; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Der Maler Leon Golub" by Jaqueline Kaess, and "Leon Golub to the Dogs" by Charlie Ahearn, 1993-2003; 2 Videocassettes (VHS); 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Leon Golub: Late Works are the Catastrophes", 2003-2005; 1 Videodiscs (DVD); 3 Videocassettes (VHS) Two tapes are labeled "latest version" and "Demo" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Addresses, undated (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    3 dismantled Rolodex files
  - Awards, 1973-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Calendars, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - Curricula Vitae, 1970s-2000s (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Educational Records, Transcripts (1938-1950), 1948-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Family Letters, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Family Party, 1996; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Genealogical Notes, circa 1983-1999; undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Service (2004 August 16) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Tribute, Cooper Union (2005 April 17) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Obituaries, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Passports and International Certificates of Vaccination, 1952-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1955-2004; Series 2; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Correspondence concerns exhibitions, projects, collectors, articles submitted for publication, Golub's work, speaking engagements, interviews, awards, political issues, gifts of artwork, studio visits, travel arrangments, and other topics regarding his professional career. Correspondents include dealers, curators, art historians, critics, collectors, writers, editors, and readers of Golub's published articles, among them: Lawrence Alloway, John Bird, Donald Kuspit, Hans-Ulrich Orist, and William Rubin.
  Correspondence is filed by year.
  - Correspondence, 1955-1999; undated (Box 2, Folder 12-32)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- Interviews, 1967-2004; Series 3; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  This series consists of edited and unedited transcripts, some published versions, a number of recorded interviews with Leon Golub, and several joint interviews with Nancy Spero. Interviews were conducted for a variety of purposes by graduate students, art historians, and others, among them: Jon Bird, Albert Elsen, Katy Kline, Hans-Ulrich Obrist, Helaine Posner, Connie Samaras, Jeanne Siegel, and David Levi Straus. Included are 1 sound reel, 7 sound cassettes, 2 8-track sound cartridges and 4 videocassettes.
  Interview transcripts and recordings are filed by date of interview; published versions are arranged by date of publication. Additional interview transcripts are scattered among the printed material (Series 7).
  - Leon Golub Interviews, Transcripts, undated; 1967-2004 (Box 3, Folder 7-19)
  - Leon Golub Interviews, Sound and Video Recordings, undated; circa 1970-1985; 2 Videocassettes (VHS); 2 Sound cartridges (8 track); 6 Sound cassettes; 1 sound tape reels (Box 3, Folder 20-23)
    Sound recordings include interviews produced by Video Data Bank, Fresh Air, and NPR, as well as interviews conducted by Studs Terkel for WFMT, Karl Fortess, and one labeled Baigell; an interview at Ox-bow, and Terkel's show on a Museum of Contemporary Art exhibition of 1974. Video includes a BBC program entitled "Modern Art Practices and Debates" taped at the Museum of Modern Art, and "Face to Face with Leon Golub."
  - Leon Golub Interviews, Video Recordings, 2000-2003; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Video recordings from Musée des Beaux Arts, Montreal and segments from the 2003 Artomi Awards.
  - Leon Golub and Nancy Spero Interviews, Transcripts, 1983-circa 2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Leon Golub and Nancy Spero Interview, Sound Recording, 1981; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Writings, 1948-2003; Series 4; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 4-5, 21
  Writings by Golub include manuscripts, notes, and printed versions of articles, catalog essays, statements, miscellaneous writings, and poems. In addition, there are also notes for talks and lectures, the transcript of a commencement address delivered at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago, and 1 sound disc of a talk given at Skowhegan. Also found are transcripts of his participation in panel discussions on politics (CAA), criticism (Douglass College), and a discussion held in conjunction with the exhibition "While the Crime is Blazing: Paintings and Drawings by Leon Golub from1994-1999."
  Writings by other authors include a dissertation, "The Art of Leon Golub: 1946-1978" by Joseph Girard Dreiss (State University of New York, Binghamton, 1980) and a thesis, "Criticism, Instigation and Inspiration in the Work of Leon Golub and Kaethe Kollwitz" by Alexandra Hirsch (The University of Michigan, 1986). Among the academic papers is "Violence, Voyeurism, and the Politics of Witnessing: Leon Golub's Mercenaries, Interrogations, and White Squad series" by Ara H. Merjian (1996). There is partial text by Arthur Danato, Robert Storr, David Levi Strauss, Robert Enright, Meeka Walsh, Robert Enright, and Douglas Dreischpoon with reproductions of Golub's artwork for a book, Leon Golub, Don't Tread on Me, Drawings: 1947-2004. Other items of note include: text of Noam Chomsky's speech at Harvard University "Intervention in Vietnam and Central America: Parallels and Differences" (1985); and notes for Joseph Girard Dreiss' remarks presented at a panel discussion, "Golub's Art: Content and Style," Corcoran Gallery of Art (1985). Also found is a sound cassette of a lecture (speaker unidentified) about modernism and its dependence on rapid communications.
  Writings are arranged by format and thereafter alphabetized by folder title. Additional writings by Golub and others are found among the subject files (Series 5); correspondence (Series 2) includes scattered statements by Golub.
  - By Golub (Box 4)
    - Articles, circa 1950s-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4-10)
    - Book Reviews, 1969-2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Editors, 1968-1969; undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Manuscripts, Miscellaneous, circa 1970s-circa 2000s; undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Notes (Box 4)
      - Clement Greenberg, circa 1962-1970s (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Irony, Modernism, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Mercs, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
      - October, Up for Grabs, Sewer Rat, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Poems, undated; 1962 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Panel Discussions, Transcripts, 1973-2002 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Speeches, Transcripts, 1957; undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Statements, circa 1948-2003 (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
    - Talk at Skowhegan, 1989; 1 Sound discs (CD) (disc 2 of 2 only, 1of 2 not found) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Talks and Lectures, 1960s-1980s; undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Theater Piece, circa 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - By Other Authors
    - Academic Papers, 1992-2002; undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Articles and Reviews, 1985-1996; undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Book, circa 2004 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Book Proposal, circa 2002 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Catalog Essay, Stedelijk Museum voor Actuele Kunst, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Dissertation, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 34-36)
    - Lecture, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Panel Discussion Notes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Poems, undated; 1996-2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Speech, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Thesis, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - By Golub (Box 21)
    - Articles, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Panel Discussion (transcript of Golub's remarks), 1973 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Subject Files, 1959-2005; Series 5; 6.2 Linear feet Boxes 5-11, OV 18
  Subject files are comprised of correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs, and audiovisual materials in varying combinations. Audiovisual recordings consist of 2 sound cassettes, 9 videocassettes, and 3 electronic discs. The files document aspects of Golub's artistic career, personal and professional interests, activities and relationships and include images of many subjects that served as source material for a variety of art projects and installations.
  Additional information about individuals, institutions, exhibitions, and events documented by subject files may be found among Golub's correspondence (Series 2). Subject files are alphabetized by title. Filing is inconsistent; for example, subject files concerning exhibitions and loans may be filed by exhibition title, museum or gallery, and occasionally by city or country.
  - 942nd Engineer Aviation Topographic Battalion, 1990s-2004 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Allan Frumkin Gallery, 1959-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Anthony Reynolds Gallery, 2000-2003 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Art Gallery of Western Australia, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Artists and Writers Protest, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Artists Call Against U.S. Intervention in Central America, 1983-1984; undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Artists Meeting for Cultural Change, undated; 1976-circa 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - artnet.com, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Atrium, Basque Center-Museum of Contemporary Art, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Austria Situation, 1998-2003; undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Baltic Centre for Contemporary Art, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Banners III Project, ALON USA/FINIA, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Barbara Gladstone Gallery, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Barbara Gross Gallery, 1992-2003; undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Baying at the Cosmos, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - BBC, "Human Rights, Human Wrongs", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - BBC, "Goya, The Private Life of a Masterpiece, The Third of May", circa 2004; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Beckmann, Max, 2001-2003 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Benefits, 1999-2004 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Benefits, Exhibitions, Projects, undated; 1980s-2002 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Bird, John, 2000-circa 2001 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Bookfair Poster, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Book Project, Interrogating Leon, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Brand X – Sacilatto Prints Project, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Brno House of Arts, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Broad, Eli, 1994-1999 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Brooklyn Museum of Art (Box 5)
    - "Leon Golub: Paintings, 1950-2000" (2001 May 18-August 19) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Lobby Project, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Vietnam II (1973) Installation (2001 May 11) (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - "Vital Forms: American Art in the Atomic Age, 1940-1960" Panel Discussion, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - "Worldwide" (1991-April 23-June 16), Includes 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 39-40)
  - Bucknell University, 1992-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Burnett Miller Gallery, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Canvas Samples, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Censorship, 1989-1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Centre de Cultura Contemporanea de Barcelona, 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chelsea Art Museum, "Anxiety" (2003 April 5-June 1) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Books, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Cultural Center, "Leon Golub: Paintings and Drawings" (2003 January 18-March 30), 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Christine König Galerie, 1997-2005 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cibachromes, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Clements, Charlie, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Courtyard Gallery, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cozier, Chris and Iréné Shaw, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cranmer Art Conservation, Inc., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Creative Time Poster, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cringe Project, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Critical Interventions: Evil" (1998) John Hansard Gallery (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Crown Gallery, 1997-2003 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Denmark, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - "Documenta II" (2001 March 14-2002 September 15), 2001-2003 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
  - Dog Book (Box 6)
    - Dog, circa 2003-2004 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1994-2004 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
    - Research Material, undated; 1980s-2001 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Source Material, undated (Box 6, Folder 26-28)
  - "Drawing Conclusions: Work by Artist-Critics, " NYArts Gallery (2003 July 9-31) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - e-Bay Complaint, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - El Salvador, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - "The End: An Independent Vision of Contemporary Culture, 1982-2000" (2000), Exit Art, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - "Erotic Drawing" (2005 January 28-March 5 and 2005, May 1-September 4), Diverse Works, Houston and The Aldrich Contemporary Art Museum, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Eshelman, Clayton, 1996-2003 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Estate Planning, 1980-1990s (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Exhibitions and Projects, 1999-2002 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - "Exhibition Momentum", undated; Oversized material housed in OV 18 (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
  - Fabric Workshop, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Fawbush Gallery, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, Award (2003), 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, "Bad Male Behavior and Women's Laughter" (2004 June 1-July 12) (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Fitzgibbon, John, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - FOGA Systems, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Franz Wynans Fine Art, Inc., 1992-1998 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Freeman, Keller Cushing, 1996-1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Galerie Akinci, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Galerie Alaine Noirhomme, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Galerie Darthea Speyer, 1987-2003 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Galerie Lelong, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Gallery Paul Anglim, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Gittoes, George, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Glasgow Gallery of Modern Art, "Sanctuary" (2003 April 11-September 29), 2002-2003; Includes 1 videodisc (DVD) (Box 7, Folder 12)